<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on @damien</title><link>https://tech.murchu.me/categories/articles/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on @damien</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tech.murchu.me/categories/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scrum for two</title><link>https://tech.murchu.me/blog/2017/09/17/scrum-for-two/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tech.murchu.me/blog/2017/09/17/scrum-for-two/</guid><description>Scrum for two? No, the title isn’t a misnomer, what follows are my experiences using scrum methodologies within a two-person team for a final year college project.
Some personal background In 2016 I found myself back in full-time education, in the midst of an aggressively paced computer science conversion course. Targeted towards existing graduates from non-computing disciplines, my classmates were a motley bunch ranging from musicians and fine artists to engineering and even agricultural graduates.</description></item><item><title>UPS on OpenShift</title><link>https://tech.murchu.me/blog/2017/05/03/ups-on-openshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tech.murchu.me/blog/2017/05/03/ups-on-openshift/</guid><description>Unified Push Server (UPS) on OpenShift Prerequisites You should have a locally installed version of OpenShift, or access to an OpenShift cluster. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have either, you can set up your own OpenShift local cluster by reading this [document]({{ &amp;ldquo;/hero-openshift&amp;rdquo; | relative_url }}).
Bringing up your cluster Bring up your cluster with:
oc cluster up --public-hostname=127.0.0.1 --host-data-dir=$HOME/os/data-dir --host-config-dir=$HOME/os/config-dir
Log into your cluster Log into your cluster via oc login</description></item><item><title>OpenShift in 30 mins</title><link>https://tech.murchu.me/blog/2017/04/27/openshift-in-30-mins/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tech.murchu.me/blog/2017/04/27/openshift-in-30-mins/</guid><description>Openshift in 30 mins with a Node.JS application Prerequisites These steps presume you already have Docker installed. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, look at this quickstart docker guide, or install Docker from here. Before you proceed any further confirm you can run docker process commands by trying docker ps
Installing Openshift Installing the oc cli tool Download the Linux oc binary and place it in your path.
Bring your cluster up Bring up your cluster for the first time by running:</description></item><item><title>Docker in 30 mins</title><link>https://tech.murchu.me/blog/2017/04/01/docker-in-30-mins/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tech.murchu.me/blog/2017/04/01/docker-in-30-mins/</guid><description>Docker in 30 mins with a Node.JS application To start using Docker for your application(s), you will need Docker installed on your machine, a node.js app you wish to containerise with Docker, and optionally a Docker Hub account to host your docker image.
Prerequisites Install docker. A list of the supported platforms and instructions for installing docker on those platforms are located here.
Before you continue, ensure you can run the docker hello-world example by running docker run hello-world in a terminal.</description></item></channel></rss>